<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.fablabni.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>FabLab</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>FabLab NI helping to deliver the first ever NI Science Festival</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/fablab-ni-helping-deliver-first-ever-ni-science-festival-0</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Friday, February 13, 2015 - 11:14&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/1601LDPP011.jpg?itok=FwZ1Rraq&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the inaugural NI Science Festival, FabLab NI in both Derry and Belfast are running a series of workshops and training sessions allowing people of all ages and from all backgrounds to get involved in the fantastic ten day long festival, aiming to inspire and teach them about the importance of science in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking place throughout the festival, FabLab at the Nerve Centre will offer teachers and students across the Key Stages the opportunity to take part in the Creating STEAM sessions. These practical sessions will be delivered using creative digital technologies, encouraging learning in STEM areas using the arts and creativity as a hook. These workshops will look at themes such as the Science of Animation, the Science of Music and the Science of Creative Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 21st February, FabLab Belfast will be bringing a pop up FabLab to the Black Box for a Maker Day, designing, hacking, gluing, printing, cutting, milling and fixing for all the family! Using our 3D printers participants will be allowed to create replicas of their own head, laser cut their own NI Science festival memento or get into electronics and learn how to solder. We’ll also demonstrate how FabLabs are designing and making weird and wonderful things from key rings, to electric cars, furniture and even fully formed houses! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also on offer at both labs as part of the festival will be Maker Taster Sessions. Open to families, groups or individuals who may be looking for a new activity that they can learn and participate in. We welcome everyone along between 10AM and 4PM on Friday 20th in Belfast and 10AM and 1PM on Saturday 21st in Derry, to design and make a variety of things using the latest in digital fabrication technologies and good old fashioned creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FabLab NI is delighted to be involved in the programme. Liam Nellis, Chair of FabLab NI Steering Committee commented;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We welcome the creation of the NI Science Festival and look forward to helping deliver this diverse and innovative programme. The FabLab is the perfect setting to learn Science through the elements of new technology. If you want to see just what you can do with a laser cutter or 3D printer, we encourage you to come along and try something new. Whether you are new to designing and making using computers or have embraced your inner maker - there’s something for you to discover and inspire!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To download the full programme for the NI Science Festival visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://nisciencefestival.com/&quot;&gt;nisciencefestival.com &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 11:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">182 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>FabLab at the Nerve Centre joins forces with Libraries NI to help young people develop digital skills.</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/fablab-nerve-centre-joins-forces-libraries-ni-help-young-people-develop-digital-skills</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Wednesday, February 4, 2015 - 13:57&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/FabLabLibrary-5.jpg?itok=Emzqfy8W&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;284&quot; /&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/FabLabLibrary-2.jpg?itok=6FKFDna_&quot; width=&quot;384&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;FabLab at the Nerve Centre has taken to the road delivering free workshops in libraries throughout the North that enable young people to focus on creativity and develop their digital skills. Funded by DCAL and SEUPB, FabLab has the ability to bring this learning to the communities and apply innovative learning in places that may not otherwise have this opportunity. So far the lab has carried out courses in Shantallow, Enniskillen and Strabane libraries with Strathfoyle, Creggan, Coleraine and Castlederg next on the list between now and next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each session involves the participants using existing library resources to identify texts and images related to their chosen subject. These artifacts are then combined within a design to make objects such as lamps and family crests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie Christie, Senior Children’s Services Manager, Libraries NI commented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;Libraries NI is delighted to work along with staff from the Nerve Centre in this very exciting project. The project presents a great opportunity for children and young people to use library resources and develop their creative skills in a library setting.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Peto, Director of Education at the Nerve Centre is pleased with how the courses have been going so far. He explained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It is great to partner with Libraries NI in such a fresh series of workshops. The team is delighted to be able to bring the innovation seen within the FabLab out in to the community and to a place where this type of skills building and learning are not typically associated. So far the courses have been a real success and there is still a chance for people to participate in Creggan, Strathfoyle, Coleraine and Castlederg. We look forward to more of this type of interaction in the future.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 13:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">179 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>FabLab NI making money for local businesses </title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/fablab-ni-making-money-local-businesses</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Tuesday, January 20, 2015 - 09:33&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/DSC_0437.jpg?itok=TrKIBsH3&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;319&quot; /&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/DSC_0473.jpg?itok=VHs65uI3&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monday morning saw businesses from across the region attend ‘Make me the Money!’ an event hosted by FabLab NI and Belfast City Council, supported by SEUPB and DCAL, to learn about the revolutionary technology within the FabLab facility and how their business can work with and benefit from it. In a time where industries are continuously striving to be at the top of their game, this innovative method in manufacturing is helping them to be just that, and all of this was demonstrated at City Hall, Belfast on Monday morning with machines in motion and businesses addressing the audience to tell their story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chairman of FabLabNI, Liam Nellis spoke at the business breakfast telling the attendees;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“3D printing, laser cutting and digital fabrication are changing the way that businesses operate across the world. From product development and design right through to packing, merchandising and point of sale materials, these tools can increase revenue and innovation in any business.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick Hurst MBE was the morning’s guest speaker and is proof of how well this technology is working for his business. He commented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“3D design and printing has revolutionised traditional ways of designing and manufacturing new product.  Lead times have been shortened and accelerated the concept to product to market life cycle.  Whale have been able to shorten their R&amp;amp;D cycle by  30% due to the invest they have made in this technology and brought concept ideas into reality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on how your business can get involved with FabLab NI visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com&quot;&gt;www.fablabni.com&lt;/a&gt; or call FabLab Belfast on 028 9075 5412 or FabLab Nerve Centre, Derry on 02871260562.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 09:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">170 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Get involved in the biggest art project in NI for 2015 and learn new skills</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/get-involved-biggest-art-project-ni-2015-and-learn-new-skills</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Monday, January 5, 2015 - 09:30&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/Temple%20image.jpg?itok=nZTGOjut&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;178&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temple by David Best&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Temple&lt;/em&gt; by David Best will mark the return of Artichoke to Derry~Londonderry.  Following their &lt;em&gt;Lumiere Derry&lt;/em&gt; event in November 2013, described as the ‘jewel in the crown’ of a momentous Year of Culture in the city and attended by 180,000 residents and visitors, Artichoke are coming back with another extraordinary experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Temple&lt;/em&gt; will be a huge construction designed and built by artist David Best, architect and designer of the temporary sculptural temples built for the annual Burning Man Festival in the Nevada Desert.  At over 60ft tall, the work will dominate the skyline on the Waterside area of the city during its week-long public exhibition. Through an extensive community engagement programme with partners including the Nerve Centre, FabLab NI, the Department for Employment and Learning and the Waterside Neighbourhood Partnership, offering apprentice, back-to-work and voluntary training schemes, &lt;em&gt;Temple&lt;/em&gt; will be built and raised by over 100 individuals drawn from communities across the city. On the evening of 21st March 2015, Temple will be ceremonially burnt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a short video on the project &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/artichoketrust/temple&quot;&gt;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/artichoketrust/temple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunities to Get Involved&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design phase for the project will open up opportunities for young people to access design technology training and obtain an Open College Network qualification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Temple &lt;/em&gt;will be constructed with a solid timber frame, which will then be clad with over 200 decorative plywood panels, each intricately designed by the artist and laser cut using CNC (Computer Numerical Control) technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The f&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;irst course commences on Monday 12th January at FabLab at the Nerve Centre and will run each day from 10am – 3.30pm until Friday 16th January. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to 20 apprentices will be trained to use computer-aided design and cutting technology as they access the Nerve Centre’s FabLab facility and work towards an OCN Level 1 qualification in Digital Fabrication.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FabLab is a digital fabrication workshop, which gives everyone in the community, from young children through to entrepreneurs, schools and community groups, the capability to turn their ideas and concepts into reality. Using open source design software and a selection of computer-controlled machines, users can design and make almost anything. FabLab is staffed by friendly, highly skilled technicians who offer support and training in the use of the equipment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apprentices will gain experience in designing individual panels for &lt;em&gt;Temple &lt;/em&gt;to be part of the finished artwork, inspired by David Best’s designs, and working under the guidance and mentorship of FabLab staff. Apprentices will be sought from across the community, and will include Key Stage 3-5 students, plus individuals drawn from local technical, arts and architecture higher education establishments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are interested or know anyone who might be, please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:gareth@celtronicfestival.com&quot;&gt;gareth.stewart@artichoke.uk.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">167 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Belfast and Dublin’s First Citizens Visit FabLab Belfast</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/belfast-and-dublin%E2%80%99s-first-citizens-visit-fablab-belfast</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Monday, January 5, 2015 - 09:22&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/IMG_4507.JPG?itok=odqWYjG3&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lord Mayor’s of both Belfast and Dublin came to witness how FabLab Belfast is inspiring a new generation of budding designers, builders, creators, problems solvers and entrepreneurs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Mayor of Belfast Cllr Nichola Mallon and Lord Mayor of Dublin, Cllr Christy Burke visited North Belfast to see how the next digital revolution is beginning to make an impact on communities, people and business across the city. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local children from Holy Family Primary School in North Belfast warmly welcomed the two mayors, and during their visit they demonstrated product design using digital fabrication equipment that is routinely used in FabLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FabLab Belfast at the Ashton Community Trust provides unique opportunities for, business to develop new products and prototypes, for schools and individuals to develop skills through accredited programmes and for communities use the knowledge and technology in the FabLab to solve problems.  FabLab emphasises how technology will bring communities and indeed cities closer together.  The recent establishment of Fab Foundation Ireland, an umbrella organization set up to co-ordinate FabLab facilities throughout the island of Ireland this will become a strength. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at the event Belfast’s Lord Mayor Nichola Mallon said: “ I’m delighted to welcome Christy to Belfast...The places we visited and people we met today are great examples of Belfast’s unsung heroes acting selflessly for the benefit of others... I think it is very important to build on the strong link we have with the city of Dublin...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Roberts Chief Executive at Ashton Community Trust said: “By harnessing the power of digital technology and internet connectivity, FabLab is the perfect way for people to be innovative and come together no matter where they are in the world. For example with this technology you can design a product in Boston and have it made in Belfast. “&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FabLabs give people access to the latest digital fabrication technologies and a range of cutting edge design software.  FabLab Belfast, opened in 2012, is run by Ashton Community Trust and is part of global network of over 400 labs from rural Africa to downtown Boston.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">166 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Major coup for FabLab Derry as DCAL commits to additional funding at Fabricating the Future conference.</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/major-coup-fablab-derry-dcal-commits-additional-funding-fabricating-future-conference</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Monday, November 10, 2014 - 15:16&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/FabLabCon041.jpg?itok=nk-w3rla&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Major coup for FabLab Derry as DCAL commits to additional funding at Fabricating the Future conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p2&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;As hundreds of people gathered in Derry’s Guildhall today to partake in Fabricating the Future, a conference hosted by FabLab NI looking at the global FabLab phenomenon, DCAL have made the announcement that the department will invest a further £350,000 in the project. £250,000 of the funding will help develop the lab within the Nerve Centre, with an additional £100,000 to develop a mobile FabLab facility which will take the lab out in to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;As the day continued, Liam Nellis Chair of FabLAB NI also revealed that the network will continue to develop further geographically, with the launch of Fab Foundation Ireland, an umbrella organization set up to co-ordinate and launch  FabLab facilities throughout the island of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;John Peto, Director of education at Nerve Centre and FabLab Derry welcomed the news. He said: ‘We are delighted with the news that DCAL will make a further investment in the FabLab project. As everyone at the conference and those who were watching the live stream have heard today, FabLabs are making a huge, positive impact within communities across the world and it is great that the department are giving us the opportunity to expand on what we are doing here. With the launch of Fab Foundation Ireland, the opportunity for expansion on the island is endless and will further benefit networks and communities working on Fabricating the Future through the work that we do at FabLab.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;The DCAL Minister, Carál Ní Chuilín said: “I am pleased to be able to confirm that I have secured capital funding to allow for the extension of the FabLab space at the Nerve Centre and for a mobile FabLab to increase outreach across the wider North West. This is part of an additional programme of investment in the North West to ensure a lasting legacy of the City of Culture year. I will be making further announcements in due course”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt; For more information on FabLab visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/&quot;&gt;www.fablabni.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 15:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">165 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>World’s Leading Practitioners In Digital Social Innovation To Speak In Derry~Londonderry</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/world%E2%80%99s-leading-practitioners-digital-social-innovation-speak-derrylondonderry</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Friday, October 24, 2014 - 12:38&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/Conference%20Invite_1.jpg?itok=cibwTl34&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;226&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of the world&#039;s leading thinkers and practitioners in digital social innovation are set to address Derry~Londonderry’s Guildhall on November 10, as part of a free conference on the global FabLab phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blair Evans of Detroit’s Incite Focus project, who has used digital technologies to drive social and economic regeneration in one of America’s most deprived cities, will be joined by speakers from Iceland - where FabLabs have played a key role in recovery from the economic catastrophe of 2008, and a host of expert speakers to discuss international best practice around the use of FabLab’s for creativity based digital social innovation at the &lt;em&gt;Fabricating the Future&lt;/em&gt; conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented by FabLab Nerve Centre and FabLab Belfast, the only facilities of their kind in Northern Ireland, the one-day event will explore how the digital fabrication model, as developed by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), is used for peace building, curriculum mapped STEM &amp;gt; STEAM learning and social innovation through Public Health, Skills and Entrepreneurship programmes across local communities in NI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Peto, director of education at Nerve Centre said: ‘We’re looking forward to welcoming all our guest speakers to Derry~Londonderry next month for what will be a thought-provoking and collaborative day with our FabLab colleagues. Not only have FabLabs allowed individuals across a wide spectrum of skills and abilities to design and make almost anything with access to state-of-the-art technology, its progressive programme has opened a world of forward-thinking creativity in local communities in Detroit, Iceland and here in Northern Ireland. This event is is the first of its kind in the UK or Ireland and we are very happy that Derry and Belfast are playing a leading role in this innovation.&#039;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will also learn about the emerging global field of digital social innovation with input from innovation charity NESTA, which facilitates practical programmes and in-depth research to help people and organisations make great ideas a reality, alongside other representatives still to be announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The afternoon will then offer the opportunity to actively discover and explore the use of digital fabrication to deliver social outcomes by engaging in a range of hands on taster sessions, demos and workshops using 3D printers, laser cutters, Arduino software and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference will also see the launch of FabLab Foundation Ireland, joining an international network formed in 2009 to facilitate and support the expansion of the FabLab model throughout the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Register to attend the conference by visiting &lt;a href=&quot;http://fablabni.com/event/fabricating-future-fablabs-and-digital-social-innovation-conference-0 &quot;&gt;http://fablabni.com/event/fabricating-future-fablabs-and-digital-social-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 12:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">164 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>FIX IT CLUB @ FABLAB BELFAST</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/fix-it-club-fablab-belfast</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Thursday, July 17, 2014 - 08:36&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/photo%202edited.JPG?itok=jXsx8Nat&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;359&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;FabLab Belfast is hosting a fix it club! Have a go at fixing and repairing your household and personal items with the help of the FabLab team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Are you tired of throwing away broken or outdated electronics and electrical equipment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Do you have something that is of importance or of value to you but needs to be repaired?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not come and learn about how you can repair your items and learn what they look like while you open them up.  We will look at how the item was designed and you will learn what makes these objects tick.  This will be open to everyone and we will be looking for some volunteers to help, especially people who can help others fix almost anything (most of us have someone like this in our family!) and we hope to make this a regualr event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cannot always promise a fix and this won’t always save money, but will give you more confidence in understanding how items are designed and how they work.  For more information about Fix It Club @ FabLab vist &lt;a href=&quot;http://fablabni.co.uk/event/fix-it-club-fablab-belfast&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 08:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">152 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Get the Summer off to a Fab start at Nerve Centre.</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/get-summer-fab-start-nerve-centre</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Wednesday, July 9, 2014 - 13:31&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/CTJ%20%285%20of%208%29.jpg?itok=QOuYdHrZ&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fab Lab Nerve are pleased to announce the latest workshops in our continuing programme that aims to bring young people together through the medium of Digital Fabrication. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be three different programmes aimed at different groups, with the first one (8th, 9th 10th July) aimed at children aged between 8 and 11, the second one ( 15th, 16th 17th July) aimed at ages 12-16, and the third one &quot;Junior steAm Academy&quot;  (21st, 22nd 23rd 24th July) aimed at those with previous Fab experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activities will range from t-shirt making to robotics, and will provide an exciting, engaging alternative for the holiday period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This programme is accessible for all ability levels, and is offered free of charge. Places are strictly limited, and prior registration is essential. For further info, contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:e.durey@nervecentre.org&quot;&gt;e.durey@nervecentre.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 13:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Nim</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">138 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>FabLab NI @ Fab10 Barcelona</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/fablab-ni-fab10-barcelona</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Wednesday, July 2, 2014 - 21:40&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/WP_20140702_17_21_07_Pro_0.jpg?itok=sK9Z38k9&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;FabLab NI  are in Barcelona this week for the annual international  FabLab conference. The team are hosting and contributing to discussion panels and workshops on the role of Fablabs in post conflict / divided societies, community engagement, and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 21:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Nim</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">137 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
