<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.fablabni.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>FabLab - BT</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/tags/bt</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>FabLab Belfast | Nerve Centre Official Launch</title>
 <link>http://www.fablabni.com/news/fablab-belfast-nerve-centre-official-launch</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-post-date&quot;&gt;Tuesday, May 21, 2013 - 23:21&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/9H0A7393.jpg?itok=2n8Jwvy6&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;346&quot; /&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/9H0A7375.jpg?itok=NNsvPufW&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; /&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/FabNerveWeb-7.jpg?itok=MCGSRfGI&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;262&quot; /&gt;&lt;img typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fablabni.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/FabNerveWeb-12.jpg?itok=4_BtDipW&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;412&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;FabLab Belfast |Nerve Centre is held its official launch on &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 22nd May&lt;/strong&gt; at Ashton Community Trust, Churchill Street , Belfast BT15 2BP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at the launch Junior Minister Jennifer McCann said: “This is a fantastic facility where both children and young people can turn their ideas into reality. This project will deliver on a number of levels, both in direct peace building activities and also as an educational tool. The inclusive nature of Fab Lab has ensured that a wide range of people from differing backgrounds can work together to build a better future for all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visitors can get their hands on manufacturing technology from precision laser cutters and 3D printers to electronic circuit fabrication equipmentTo date, thousands of small manufacturers, inventors, schools and community groups worldwide have used Fab Lab’s resources resulting in a wide range of products having been successfully conceived, developed and prototyped there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior Minister Jonathan Bell added: “Fab Lab is a first class example of the type of challenging and ground breaking work at local level that is laying the foundations for a united, shared future for everyone in Northern Ireland. Fab Lab is a prime example of positive social intervention. It has spread to over 200 locations worldwide and we’re glad to have it in Northern Ireland.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcoming the project Pat Colgan, Chief Executive of the Special EU Programmes Body, said: “This is a truly innovate project and one which we were pleased to support under the EU’s PEACE III Programme. It has created a new, shared space where people from all communities can come together and develop their creative and entrepreneurial skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It will encourage greater levels of positive cross-community contact and increase the capacity and employment potential for people living within deprived areas of the region. The project will also link into and share experiences with the larger worldwide ‘Fab Lab’ network.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Morris, BT Director of Corporate Services, which supports Fab Lab in Belfast through its BT Connected Communities programme said: “We are delighted to support the Ashton Centre by providing volunteers from BT’s Technology Service and Operations division to work with people in the local area to help them achieve their potential.  The Fab Lab is a fantastic coup for the local community, Northern Ireland and Ireland. The idea is to give people access to the tools needed to bring product ideas to life, alongside skills training to help develop new designs and prototypes. We hope that the Fab Labs will see enormous success and growth over the coming years and help boost local industry and encourage the next generation of innovators not just on a local platform but globally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Neil Gershenfeld, Director, MIT Center for Bits and Atoms recorded a video message that was played at the launch, he said: &quot;We&#039;re delighted to welcome flagship Fab Labs in Belfast and Derry/Londonderry to the global fab lab network. We&#039;ve enjoyed working with the lively communities at the Nerve and Ashton Centres, and look forward to helping launch Fab Labs in Northern Ireland to empower anyone to make (almost) anything.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Roberts, Chief Executive of Ashton Community Trust said he was pleased the Fablabs were situated right in the heart of two communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Fab Lab is truly a gateway to life-long learning opportunities. Through the provision of digital fabrication technologies we are beginning to see how important gaining these skills will be to the development of the local workforce and future generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ashton Community Trust is a charity dedicated to social enterprise and regeneration and we are very proud to see Fab Lab become part of our day-to-day portfolio of community-focused services. It has the potential to spark creativity and entrepreneurship across a wide spectrum of local people and also influence the educational and business sectors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;label-above&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/launch&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Launch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/seupb&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;SEUPB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/bt&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;BT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 23:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">52 at http://www.fablabni.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
